okay so in this case we have a desktop
that we have access to and we're going
to go ahead and start PS attack and the
first thing I'm gonna want to do is find
some passwords so I'm gonna run get
attack passwords so that we can see what
commands we have available to us that
will give us passwords a lot of that
comes from inve which acts as a relay to
capture hashes between SMB and HTTPS and
you know things like that really cool
tool but what we're looking for
specifically here is the invoke GPP
password or I get GPP password command
lit what this does is gets the passwords
that have been set through group policy
say for example you wanted to find a
local admin account or set up a schedule
task that uses credentials you could do
that through group policy and we can use
get GPB password to find those passwords
and decrypt them so we ran GPP password
we got a hit back for an account called
robot and we can see it's password here
and it looks like this was a set up as a
scheduled task or something to that
effect so the next thing I want to do is
see if I could find out some more about
this robot account so we're going to use
get attack to find commands that are
related to Active Directory and there's
a lot of stuff here a lot of great recon
tools provided by the largely by the
Power View module basically a lot of
ways to look at what's going on in
Active Directory find a lot of
information that's out there we want to
find out specific things about a user
account so we're gonna look for is
something that you know relates to users
and looks like we have what we're
looking for here a command line called
get net user that's gonna query
information for a given user from the
domain so let's run get net user and
robot and that kid says back all this
information about the robot account we
can see how many bat log ons it's had we
could see that it's a
service account for his stuff one of the
interesting things about this is the
fact that he's a member of a group
called local admin which sounds really
promising but to confirm what we think
this means let's go ahead and look at
the local groups on this machine so
let's run get attack a search for a
group a lot of stuff comes back about
what's interesting to us whoops
what's interesting to us is the fine
group was it there we go getnet local
group and what that's going to do is
exactly what it sounds like list all the
current users in a specified local group
so let's take a look at how we're gonna
use this so we can run get help and that
returns the help for getnet local group
looks like we can run this against a
remote computer if we wanted to but it
seems pretty basic we just have to feed
it a group name and it should get us
what we're looking for so let's run get
that local group we're gonna pass it the
group name parameter and we're gonna
pass it administrators because we're
interested and the local administrators
group all right so that returns
everything looks like we have a couple
users in here an administrator an admin
account we have the obviously the domain
admins and we have our ad group of local
admin so robot should be a local
administrator on this box so let's go
ahead and restart PS attack this time it
has that robot account
great so we know that we have local
admin on this box or we suspect we do so
let's go ahead and look for some attacks
and ways that we can investigate further
on a local admin access so there are two
commands one is invoke check local admin
access that we're gonna be looking at
here and the other is find local admin
access invoke check local admin access
is just going to tell us whether the
instance that we're running has
administrative access
whereas find local admin access is
actually going to go throughout the
network and find other machines that we
have local admin access on so running
invoke check local admin access does
tell us that this is an administrative
instance so let's see what other
computers we have admin access on so it
came back with two labs 7-1 and lab 7 -
2 lab 7 - one is the machine that we're
on currently lab 7 - 2 is another
machine in the network now the next
thing I want to do is I want to find
some administrators some domain
administrators so I know there's a
command here to find administrators so
we go ahead and do a get attack for fine
and it looks like we have a invoke user
hunter which is a really cool tool it's
going to find machines on the local
network that they have users logged in
who are a member of a specific group
we're looking for so let's go ahead and
look at how we're going to run invoke
user hunter by using the get help
command alright so there are a lot of
parameters here this is kind of an
overwhelming amount of options so let's
go ahead and look at the examples that
get help provides for invoke user hunter
all right so this is a lot more
straightforward we have eight examples
of how to use it and it looks like the
first example here is going to do
exactly what we want
it's going to find machines on local
domain where domain admins are logged
into it's also going to check if the
current user has local admin on that box
so let's go ahead and run that invoke
user hunter - check access and it came
back with a hit looks like we have a
domain admin named admin one logged on
to lab seven - - and we do have local
admin access on that box so what we're
gonna want to do here is run mimic ATS
against it and see if we can't get his
passwords if you're not familiar with
mimic ATS basically maquettes is like a
Swiss Army knife of Windows credentials
and tokens it can do all sorts of stuff
but what we're mainly going to use it
for them what a lot of people use it for
is dumping credentials out of memory so
we're gonna go ahead and run get - help
and then invoke mimikatz and see what's
required here to run mimic ads looks
like we need a computer name and then
we'll pass it the dump creds parameter
so let's go ahead and do that now we're
gonna pass it labs 7-2 which is that
machine the domain admins logged into
and dump creds
all right so we got back a lot of
information here looks like we have the
hashes for the computer account and we
have the admins password see if we have
anything else interested in here nope so
we have the credentials for a domain
admin let's go ahead and make a note of
that password let's go ahead and restart
PS tag now as a domain admin and what
I'm interested in now is getting the
Active Directory database because I
don't know how much longer I have to sit
at this computer so let's go ahead and
get that database we can take it offline
and get cracking
the first thing I'm gonna want to do
though is find out where a domain
controller is what is what's a domain
controller on the network so we're gonna
do get attack and then domain controller
it's gonna return us a couple options
here the one we're looking for is
getting a domain controller which is
just going to return us a list of main
controllers on the pane so there is one
domain controller here we can see it's
FISMA roles the IP address what site
it's in and its host name next thing
that we want to do is find out how we're
gonna actually copy the NTDs file so we
do get attacked and copy now returns a
handful of utilities or commandlets a
lot of them dealing with volume Shadow
Copy tools which is pretty cool but the
one that we're interested in is invoke -
ninja copy and what that's going to do
is it's really interesting it analyzes
the raw data of the volume and recreates
that parses it back into NTFS structures
so it kind of recreates the vows from
the raw data of the volume this is gonna
help us get around file locks and stuff
like that because we're kind of coming
in around from the side to get to this
data so let's look at what's required to
run and vote ninja copy
so we have a couple options here looks
like we can pass it a remote destination
computer name local destination this is
a little confusing so let's go ahead and
look at what the examples are for invoke
ninja copy it looks like the first one
is gonna do what we want we're going to
get the NTDs zip file from a remote
server pass it to local server we need a
path a computer name and a local
destination so let's go ahead and run
that we're gonna pass it the path to
NTDs net we're gonna pass it the
computer name for the domain controller
which was lab 2012 and we need a local
destination so we're gonna go ahead and
copy it to the file or the folder that
we're working out of ctools
and we're gonna call it NTD guessed it
now this is going to take a little bit
to run because you know it is doing some
low-level disk work here but we'll let
it run
alright let's go ahead and list out the
directory and there is our NTDs net